<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Deltastring: Zendesk migrations, automations, integrations, applications | CX services agency, London, UK</title>
    <description>Expert Zendesk migrations, automations, integrations, applications. Streamline your customer experience with boutique Zendesk agency services from Southampton, UK.</description>
    <link>https://deltastring.com/</link>
    <atom:link href="https://deltastring.com/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/>
    <pubDate>Mon, 20 Oct 2025 23:00:08 +0100</pubDate>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 20 Oct 2025 23:00:08 +0100</lastBuildDate>
    <generator>Jekyll v4.3.4</generator>
    
      <item>
        <title>Moral Support, the rising tide edition</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/img/moral-support-header.png&quot; alt=&quot;Moral Support Header&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Hello! Yes I’m a little later than usual. I don’t normally like to publish on Linkedin on Fridays but it has been a hectic week and Friday has come along and I hadn’t written a newsletter but I do have things I want to say so here we all are. Do you have big weekend plans?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We’ve had good chats with some partners of Deltastring over the last week or so and one thing we’ve been sharing is our perspective on these agreements, more informal alliances, basically helping each other out.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I think there’s a difficult balancing act with partnership agreements. Some businesses make the bulk of their revenue through referral agreements. Vendors see them as outsourced sales teams on a commission only basis. These businesses typically sign partnerships with every vendor going, so any client needing any product can lead to some circulation of money. Does this add value?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;My instinct has always been to exercise caution about who we work with. For one thing, I am not a sales person! I’m not going to be pitching your thing and building pipeline or using any sales terminology. What I will be doing is solving problems for my clients! If you have a good solution then I will do the introductions.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://deltastring.com/assets/img/juice.jpeg&quot; alt=&quot;Human needed!&quot; /&gt;
&lt;em&gt;Grabbing a juice between meetings. This is the new healthy me, cutting down on energy drinks!&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So why not agree to every partnership which comes across my desk? Well I think a part of it is lending some reputation, sharing some credibility with products, it’s not really my style. When we do work with a vendor it is usually not primarily because we love the product and the value it brings (though that is a prerequisite) but because the people of that business are humans who we can rely on to provide great service to our clients. Great service is the business we’re in!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;That seems complicated and limiting, I appreciate. So why do it at all, why not just shun partnerships and let clients shop around?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The answer is that I am not someone who wants to scrap for a bigger slice of a fixed size pie. I want the pie itself to grow much bigger and so we can all make a good living! A healthy ecosystem around a platform is the best way to keep us all busy and provide great outcomes for our clients.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Co-operation is the key to rising the tide which floats all our ships. That’s not to say healthy competition doesn’t keep us all honest and focused! What we love about the people we do partner with is how we can be human with them and keep looking to what’s next, which is continuing to use technology and human ingenuity to provide great results for our customers.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Sat, 11 Oct 2025 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate>
        <link>https://deltastring.com/2025/10/11/moral-support-the-rising-tide-edition/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">https://deltastring.com/2025/10/11/moral-support-the-rising-tide-edition/</guid>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Moral Support, the Rosie edit</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/img/moral-support-header.png&quot; alt=&quot;Moral Support Header&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This week’s feature is from the brain and keyboard of my fellow Deltastring founder Rosie Elliott-Welch.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;where-is-the-humanity&quot;&gt;Where is the humanity?&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Plenty of people in my life have done their time working customer facing roles, in one form or another, so when they have a bad experience with a business it comes up in conversation. This has only increased now I’m running my business Deltastring and working with brands my friends have heard of!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Increasingly the object of their ire is an AI bot which stood between customer and human agent. It’s frustrating when you feel like this is a quick solve for a human but the bot isn’t quite grasping what you’re asking.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Most people are well aware that if they repeatedly ask for a human it will usually be escalated. I’ve been considering the implications for the human agents. There could be hundreds of messages over multiple threads before the point where real eyeballs look at the situation.I realised that it turns regular agents into unwilling supervisors. Typing I WANT A HUMAN to a chat bot is the equivalent of asking for the manager. We’ve rearranged the hierarchy without consideration for how this impacts experiences.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://deltastring.com/assets/img/need-a-human.png&quot; alt=&quot;Human needed!&quot; /&gt;
&lt;em&gt;Just get a human person please!&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;After my years as a retailer I know that some proportion of people will always demand an escalation even after good service, even when their problems were solved. Sales assistants can usually rapidly identify customer intention. Training new hires includes reminding how humans communicate with tone to a greater degree than words themselves. I’m sure most of you have been shown a pie chart of Albert Mehrabian’s 7-38-55 Communication model, however misinterpreted that tool is! No AI can understand these nuances quite like a human can.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When the bot gets it wrong, or the customer expects human service at the point of contact we are creating a point of contention before the issue is even raised, and when it’s escalated the agent has to smooth over the experience the customer has had at the very beginning of the conversation. We’re starting on the back foot.I think we have to acknowledge that if AI agents are implemented that we are expecting agents to deal with customers who will resent having to interact with it. Although basic queries may be answered by not validating customers with personal service there is now extra escalation created by simply having AI agents.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Ultimately, every business has to balance a range of opposing demands. Providing support is expensive, but it provides valuable insight to steer product development. Customers want more, faster, better, but they don’t want prices to shoot up. Businesses need to be on top of technology, and avoid getting left behind by more agile competitors. Where is the tipping point? Ask your agents, your customers are telling them!&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Thu, 25 Sep 2025 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate>
        <link>https://deltastring.com/2025/09/25/moral-support-the-rosie-edit/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">https://deltastring.com/2025/09/25/moral-support-the-rosie-edit/</guid>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Moral Support plays musical chairs</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/img/moral-support-header.png&quot; alt=&quot;Moral Support Header&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;more-support-more-morality&quot;&gt;More support, more morality&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We’re switching up Moral Support from fortnightly to weekly. It looks like a fortnightly newsletter isn’t ideal for distribution. Weekly editions put us in sync with Zendesk release notes and other cycles.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You might also notice less formality and more personal views here. If there’s one goal I have for the rest of 2025 it’s to play my part in bringing the humanity back to what we all do. I think everyone in the support or customer experience trade does understand and believe in the importance of being there for the humans who use the products and services we represent.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;when-the-music-stops&quot;&gt;When the music stops&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Transfer deadline day in the football world has been and gone but over here in business operations tooling it feels like an ever accelerating game of musical chairs.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;One trend I can’t get behind is the pre-recorded video “interview” people keep discussing. If you’re not familiar, basically you are sent some questions and told to film yourself answering them. There are even new SaaS products like &lt;a href=&quot;https://hirevue.com/?hellofromdeltastringdotcom&quot;&gt;Hirevue&lt;/a&gt; which pour AI over the asymmetrical hiring process.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Here is the thing they are trying to eradicate. Good hiring is when both parties make a positive decision to collaborate. The best outcomes happen when goals align. No good relationship starts with imbalance.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The interview format exists because the candidate is auditioning the employer just as much as the reverse. A good interview has thoughtful questions and detailed responses on each side and the candidate leaves with a strong sense of the processes and values at the business as well as good understanding of their role and the structure around them.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The video recording step presumes that the candidate has no agency and they do not have the right to answers at this stage. It filters for applicants who will jump through hoops when ordered. It is a demonstration that the company wants you to know from the very first interaction that they hold all the cards. If you’re not happy with it, someone else probably will be.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://deltastring.com/assets/img/zoom.png&quot; alt=&quot;Nico, working&quot; /&gt;
&lt;em&gt;Webcam shot. Not the look I’d choose for an interview.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It’s almost certainly a waste of time anyway. Cold applications are so rarely successful now. There is usually already a preferred candidate known to the decision maker and they will skip this stage or be told it’s a formality. The role of the people who cold apply is to be a yardstick, benchmarking for the salary of the chosen person and a reference point in terms of skills and ability and experience.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;My strong recommendation is to always say “thanks but I don’t do these, but let us book in a conversation about the position.” Avoid going through the application process at all until you’ve identified the person who this role would report to and asked them for an informal chat about the position. Never send a CV until you are specifically asked to provide a CV.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you’re taking time to line up your next opportunity, consider changing your approach to put yourself in a more balanced position.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;latest-with-zendesk&quot;&gt;Latest with Zendesk&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It’s an in-between time for product updates and there is precisely one item this week: Copilot intelligent triage for voice calls.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We have been made aware of new developments in the ongoing conflict between former stockholders and the board of Zendesk inc. I’m no legal expert and certainly won’t be making any attempt to explain the report from the Delaware Supreme Court last week but I link to an article &lt;a href=&quot;www.law360.com/articles/2386403/del-justices-urged-to-revive-10-5b-zendesk-deal-challenge&quot;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt; (soft paywall) for those who want to keep an eye on these things.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We also have the end date for Zendesk Sell reported as the 31st August 2027. If you’re a Sell user you are probably well aware that it is being wound down and you need to have plans in place to migrate. My feeling is that a more focused approach from Zendesk will be the correct choice.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Wed, 17 Sep 2025 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate>
        <link>https://deltastring.com/2025/09/17/moral-support-musical-chairs/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">https://deltastring.com/2025/09/17/moral-support-musical-chairs/</guid>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Moral Support reads the news</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/img/moral-support-header.png&quot; alt=&quot;Moral Support Header&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;how-are-you&quot;&gt;How are you?&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Let’s normalise just saying “How are you?” instead of “I hope you’re well” which really means “Don’t you tell me about your problems” doesn’t it?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;At Deltastring we start from the position “Good customer service is its own reward” and then when the processes are good our clients can use the enhanced data, the released agent capacity, the fresh insights from the customers, however they see fit. “How are you?” is a part of this. Not that vague of course, but we can absolutely throw in “How are you finding the product?” type questions.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Businesses worry about asking open questions, or inviting negativity. When I had restaurants, I always instructed my teams against asking closed or assumptive questions. We’re not afraid of hearing where we can do better. When someone has something to say, they are giving us the gift of an opportunity to act and improve. If they aren’t happy, thank them! I’m so grateful you shared this with us. It’s only through the honesty that we can continue to improve.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We don’t always get things right, and neither do you. Being perfect isn’t the goal. Being better tomorrow than we were yesterday, that’s what today is about. So how are you?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;housekeeping&quot;&gt;Housekeeping&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Even though I was told in the comments on the &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.linkedin.com/posts/nicoboyce_zendesk-activity-7366104394745929728-oxmi&quot;&gt;Linkedin post&lt;/a&gt; regarding the relaunched &lt;a href=&quot;https://deltastring.com/news/&quot;&gt;Deltastring Zendesk ecosystem news page&lt;/a&gt; I was still was surprised and delighted to see our mention on &lt;a href=&quot;https://internalnote.com/zendesk-news-roundup-for-september-2025/?hey-from-deltastring&quot;&gt;Internal Note&lt;/a&gt;. I make no secret of the fact that the contribution to the ecosystem that Thomas makes is a huge inspiration to me and how I try and do business, so this is a gesture I appreciate.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In the same spirit, I am sure mamy of our readers will find great value in &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.linkedin.com/pulse/get-involved-remote-creatives-barbados-other-news-han-talbot-5ydxe/&quot;&gt;The Remote Creatives&lt;/a&gt; where marketing strategist Han lives the values she espouses, building in public and bringing her community with her. Highly recommended.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;notes-on-news&quot;&gt;Notes on News&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Since relaunching our &lt;a href=&quot;https://deltastring.com/news/&quot;&gt;Zendesk ecosystem news page&lt;/a&gt;, I’ve had several conversations about the thinking behind it. Here’s some thoughts on why I built it and how it works.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I was a big user of RSS before social media made these feeds less common. Sites such as Digg and Reddit were for a time great places to track news and views. I check &lt;a href=&quot;https://news.ycombinator.com/&quot;&gt;Hacker News&lt;/a&gt; at least daily. I don’t feel like Substack and newsletters quite fill the niche of well-curated aggregation. Essentially it’s a case of building something I wanted to use, then later making it available for other people. Turns out there’s a bit of an audience out there!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;RSS (and I’m including Atom and other syndication formats) is a broad and vague specification. I can’t go to other websites and tell them they need to change the way they build their feed. I did have a chat with one source when we did identify an issue but we needed a robust and consistent way of parsing feeds.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Plenty of places don’t even do RSS now so alternative methods are needed. I’m pretty handy with Python library BeautifulSoup. If you’re curious about scraping, start with &lt;a href=&quot;https://automatetheboringstuff.com/&quot;&gt;Automate the Boring Stuff&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div style=&quot;text-align: center;&quot;&gt;
&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/img/cover-automate3.webp&quot; alt=&quot;Automate the Boring Stuff&quot; /&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The problem is it ends up being very individual for each source. There’s another batch of sources on the way but we’re talking to the publishers where we can and trying to do things properly first time.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When there’s a big story, every website in the industry reproduces the news with little variation. It’s 2025, there’s a lot of ChatGPT regurgitation. Before adding the system to group and combine and summarise stories then the whole page would be one long list of every website publishing the same item. This is no use to anyone! One of those cases where LLMs caused the problem but provided the solution.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I think it’s important to build the tools you yourself can get value from. Look at &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=d3QzjCzaWOA&quot;&gt;Beacon, our upcoming Zendesk configuration management tool&lt;/a&gt; - this is something I built for myself originally and it’s going to be a hit with people who have other duties besides Zendesk administration.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Traffic is very healthy but I wouldn’t be worried if it was only us checking the page, because it is useful for our work. I think it’s only me who listens to my &lt;a href=&quot;https://open.spotify.com/album/4xJSB3h9sIeyMfpmZZmB8n&quot;&gt;latest album&lt;/a&gt; but I’m still glad I write music.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;People are very open to these sorts of ideas in the Zendesk ecosystem. Honestly it has been said that Zendesk Inc are not the best stewards of the community around the product but ultimately the reason we all do Zendesk is because we want to provide great support. That support can be for each other too!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I like to surround myself with people who think the same way, we’re talking the Kilted Consultant Jason McDonald, Ultimate specialist Jake Samson, Zendesk engineering guru Anthony Stenhouse, people who solve their own problems and this gives them great capability to service their clients.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/img/zendeskers.jpeg&quot; alt=&quot;Zendeskers&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Thu, 04 Sep 2025 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate>
        <link>https://deltastring.com/2025/09/04/moral-support-reads-the-news/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">https://deltastring.com/2025/09/04/moral-support-reads-the-news/</guid>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Moral Support, the heatwave edition</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;Hello Zendeskers! By Zendesker I mean people whose work is primarily based around operating a Zendesk instance. Did you know internally at Zendesk they call the team Zendeskians? But of course not all Zendeskians are Zendeskers according to my definition a couple of sentences ago. You can draw your own Venn diagram if you so wish.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I hope you’re keeping cool if you’re somewhere this heatwave is happening. My Scottish genes didn’t equip me for summer. There’s a bit of a breeze in a certain spot but if I work there I seem to be targeted by bees. Maybe the Deltastring orange colour scheme looks floral to this swarm? Anyway I will keep this one brief!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Back to Venn diagrams which have been a theme for me this week as two of our projects have involved untangling legacy trigger conditions. We’re lucky to work with great clients and swarms of smart engineers but everyone gets muddled with their any and all conditions occasionally. We talked them each through it with the aid of Venn and redesigned the process for the new channels and workflows.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Side note: if ever you’re passing through Cambridge, see if the porters will let you take a look at the Gonville &amp;amp; Caius college dining hall, where the windows commemorate John Venn, Francis Crick, alongside other Caius alumni.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/img/caius-dining-hall.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;The dining hall at Caius&quot; /&gt;
&lt;em&gt;The dining hall at Caius. Spot the Venn diagram window?&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Here’s another set theory intersection. Consider the people within your company and the people within a competitor and the links between. There will be some connections usually! Do your competitors deal with similar challenges? If they did, would you be able to collaborate?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;However, there are companies who aren’t competing with you who do share similar problems. They might have good solutions for things which are causing you headaches! Is there any crossover between these companies? Who is in the intersection of that Venn diagram?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;That’s your implementation consultants. We go business to business and we cross-pollinate ideas and solutions and processes and also introduce people or other vendors. It’s in the nature of what we do!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;youtube-facade&quot; style=&quot;position: relative; overflow: hidden; width: 100%; aspect-ratio: 16/9; background-color: #000; cursor: pointer; max-width: 560px; margin: 0 auto;&quot; data-video-id=&quot;ETlLIyQ42iY&quot;&gt;
  &lt;img src=&quot;https://img.youtube.com/vi/ETlLIyQ42iY/maxresdefault.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Star Wars Contracting video thumbnail&quot; style=&quot;width: 100%; height: 100%; object-fit: cover;&quot; loading=&quot;lazy&quot; /&gt;
  &lt;button class=&quot;youtube-play-button&quot; style=&quot;position: absolute; top: 50%; left: 50%; transform: translate(-50%, -50%); width: 68px; height: 48px; background-color: #212121; opacity: 0.8; border-radius: 14%; border: none; cursor: pointer;&quot; aria-label=&quot;Play video&quot;&gt;
    &lt;svg height=&quot;100%&quot; version=&quot;1.1&quot; viewBox=&quot;0 0 68 48&quot; width=&quot;100%&quot;&gt;
      &lt;path class=&quot;ytp-large-play-button-bg&quot; d=&quot;M66.52,7.74c-0.78-2.93-2.49-5.41-5.42-6.19C55.79,.13,34,0,34,0S12.21,.13,6.9,1.55 C3.97,2.33,2.27,4.81,1.48,7.74C0.06,13.05,0,24,0,24s0.06,10.95,1.48,16.26c0.78,2.93,2.49,5.41,5.42,6.19 C12.21,47.87,34,48,34,48s21.79-0.13,27.1-1.55c2.93-0.78,4.64-3.26,5.42-6.19C67.94,34.95,68,24,68,24S67.94,13.05,66.52,7.74z&quot; fill=&quot;#f00&quot;&gt;&lt;/path&gt;
      &lt;path d=&quot;M 45,24 27,14 27,34&quot; fill=&quot;#fff&quot;&gt;&lt;/path&gt;
    &lt;/svg&gt;
  &lt;/button&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;script src=&quot;/assets/js/youtube-facade.js&quot;&gt;&lt;/script&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Consider ways you can contribute to or benefit from sharing and collaborating. For those of use who are Zendeskers or indeed Zendeskians, everyone wins when we can build on good solutions and exchange ways to get the best out of our tools.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I’m off to grab something in the intersection of caffeinated and ice cold and delicious, then get back to some solution design. Have a productive week!&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Wed, 02 Jul 2025 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate>
        <link>https://deltastring.com/2025/07/02/moral-support-the-heatwave-edition/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">https://deltastring.com/2025/07/02/moral-support-the-heatwave-edition/</guid>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Moral Support (Atkins edition)</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;Hello! We’re keeping it lightweight today. I don’t think I’ve ever had a busier fortnight than between the last Moral Support and now as I sit down to write this in the new house, in between calls on new projects. At least the weather has improved and I haven’t needed the &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.linkedin.com/company/zendesk/?lipi=urn%3Ali%3Apage%3Ad_flagship3_pulse_read%3BcMaA5lYTQMCrsAF0gkH%2BvQ%3D%3D&quot;&gt;Zendesk umbrella&lt;/a&gt; so much.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Thanks to everyone I’ve had a call with over the last week or so for making the same “I see you unpacked the important things” joke seeing the rack of guitars in frame. You should check out &lt;a href=&quot;https://nicoboyce.com/2025/04/22/releasing-music-for-drecks/&quot;&gt;the new album&lt;/a&gt;! You can’t be all work and no play, so yes, the laptops and the guitars moved first.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Anyway, back to business.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;the-big-results-are-still-made-up-of-all-the-little-changes&quot;&gt;The big results are still made up of all the little changes&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We’ve got a real interesting mix of clients right now, from new to old, from utilities to cutting edge tech, from enormous corporations to two-pizza orgs. Yet the same is true in all of these businesses. Big results come from many tiny changes.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I enjoy a big migration project, these so-called “digital transformation” events. It’s great to see agents jumping into a Zendesk instance feeling unshackled from the limitations of how they were previously working. Here’s what the sales people don’t tell you though. The real power of these projects is that it’s a good opportunity to abandon all the legacy workflows and go back to basics, rebuilding your processes for tomorrow rather than yesterday.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Here’s a video I like and you should watch where I talk about our approach to process design.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;youtube-facade&quot; style=&quot;position: relative; overflow: hidden; width: 100%; aspect-ratio: 16/9; background-color: #000; cursor: pointer; max-width: 560px; margin: 0 auto;&quot; data-video-id=&quot;zjwyzpqc6Vg&quot;&gt;
  &lt;img src=&quot;https://img.youtube.com/vi/zjwyzpqc6Vg/maxresdefault.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Process design approach video thumbnail&quot; style=&quot;width: 100%; height: 100%; object-fit: cover;&quot; loading=&quot;lazy&quot; /&gt;
  &lt;button class=&quot;youtube-play-button&quot; style=&quot;position: absolute; top: 50%; left: 50%; transform: translate(-50%, -50%); width: 68px; height: 48px; background-color: #212121; opacity: 0.8; border-radius: 14%; border: none; cursor: pointer;&quot; aria-label=&quot;Play video&quot;&gt;
    &lt;svg height=&quot;100%&quot; version=&quot;1.1&quot; viewBox=&quot;0 0 68 48&quot; width=&quot;100%&quot;&gt;
      &lt;path class=&quot;ytp-large-play-button-bg&quot; d=&quot;M66.52,7.74c-0.78-2.93-2.49-5.41-5.42-6.19C55.79,.13,34,0,34,0S12.21,.13,6.9,1.55 C3.97,2.33,2.27,4.81,1.48,7.74C0.06,13.05,0,24,0,24s0.06,10.95,1.48,16.26c0.78,2.93,2.49,5.41,5.42,6.19 C12.21,47.87,34,48,34,48s21.79-0.13,27.1-1.55c2.93-0.78,4.64-3.26,5.42-6.19C67.94,34.95,68,24,68,24S67.94,13.05,66.52,7.74z&quot; fill=&quot;#f00&quot;&gt;&lt;/path&gt;
      &lt;path d=&quot;M 45,24 27,14 27,34&quot; fill=&quot;#fff&quot;&gt;&lt;/path&gt;
    &lt;/svg&gt;
  &lt;/button&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;script src=&quot;/assets/js/youtube-facade.js&quot;&gt;&lt;/script&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you’re not sure where to start with a fresh round of modernising, it’s almost certainly reporting. Get really good data and the opportunities present themselves!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Sometimes you need to get that data in front of people who are going to have trouble making a habit of checking a dashboard. I was glad to be able to help out this Support Driven user with a tiny piece of useful info!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/img/explore.png&quot; alt=&quot;Support Driven screenshot&quot; /&gt;
&lt;em&gt;A helpful tip for getting reporting data in front of the right people&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The work we do at Deltastring is built on a few thousand of these tiny pieces of knowledge across Zendesk and dozens of other products. I’m sure it’s the same at your company. Why not set up a little channel in your Slack (or Teams or wherever) for surfacing the little tips and hacks that make everyone’s work easier? Then make sure to review and collate and archive periodically.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;new-structure-at-deltastring&quot;&gt;New structure at Deltastring&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Today we’re making the first of a series of announcements about organisational change here at Deltastring Ltd.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;My fellow founder Rosie Elliott-Welch is stepping away from the day-to-day contract services work and into the position of CEO of Deltastring. Rosie will continue to own all the background processes. My job title will change to CTO and we’re going to look to fill other roles through the coming weeks and months as well as continue to work with our freelance network.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This change reflects the shift in emphasis from being a provider of technical consulting services to being a business with an offering including these services but also providing products and tools and potentially managed services and outsourced processes.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Now I’ve got my office mostly reassembled watch this space for more news on &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=d3QzjCzaWOA&quot;&gt;Beacon, the Deltastring tool for Zendesk configuration management&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Have a great week, may all your CSATs be positive!&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Thu, 19 Jun 2025 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate>
        <link>https://deltastring.com/2025/06/19/moral-support-atkins-edition/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">https://deltastring.com/2025/06/19/moral-support-atkins-edition/</guid>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Moral Support, the flip-flops edition</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;Hello. How are you? It’s definitely summer now here in Hampshire, which affects highly seasonal businesses in different ways. If your busy period is winter, you’ll be looking ahead and focusing on preparation. If summer is your busiest time then you’ll be thinking about the here and now and also the recent past. Did you make the right changes over the last few months?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In my previous career in the pub trade, my mentor Stuart liked to be making plenty of cash all year round. His was very much a winter pub, so he invested in some summer opportunities each year to keep his team busy. We’re talking a bottle shop near the beach, beer festivals, that sort of thing.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It’s true with the economy too. Some businesses thrive in a rising market. Others have methods to grow in generally more difficult times. We also see this phenomena on a smaller scale as users net shift between a duopoly, such as to and from Apple products. Phone accessory manufacturers don’t mind that at all!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;At Deltastring we think of it this way: some bet on the tide coming in and some bet on the tide going out but the real energy is in the back and forth of the waves.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I guess this is a long-winded way of encouraging you to look at how you can make the most of the opportunities that exist for you, using winter rather than wishing for summer all year round!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;feature-creep&quot;&gt;Feature creep&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The comment from &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.linkedin.com/feed/update/urn:li:activity:7335239341721468930&quot;&gt;Gareth Elsby on this post&lt;/a&gt; had me thinking about documentation.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If no one knows that something can be done then it might as well not be possible.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Zendesk is a huge and mighty platform and even the most experienced of Zendesk specialists are learning all the time. Earlier I mentioned to someone “oh you can check the IPs page” but they had never known about &lt;code class=&quot;language-plaintext highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;[subdomain].zendesk.com/ips&lt;/code&gt; and I’m sure there are still things like that I don’t know yet.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;What’s the solution? As always, I think the ecosystem should solve this problem with some collaboration. If someone starts a Zendesk wiki then I have plenty of material for it already!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;its-pride-month&quot;&gt;It’s pride month&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Be kind to your queer friends (of all flavours) because it’s a tough old world lately. Challenge businesses who post pinkwashing adverts “Can you say trans women are women?” and please choose to speak up when something needs to be said.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;we-are-all-systems-go-with-our-product-launch&quot;&gt;We are all systems go with our product launch&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In the spirit of “be the change you want to see” or whatever the phrase is, we are gearing up to welcome paying users into our SaaS product which we’ve used internally for some time.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It’s called Beacon and we hope it will revolutionise Zendesk maintenance for support leaders who are juggling other responsibilities. Take a look at this and see what you think!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;youtube-facade&quot; style=&quot;position: relative; overflow: hidden; width: 100%; aspect-ratio: 16/9; background-color: #000; cursor: pointer; max-width: 560px; margin: 0 auto;&quot; data-video-id=&quot;d3QzjCzaWOA&quot;&gt;
  &lt;img src=&quot;https://img.youtube.com/vi/d3QzjCzaWOA/maxresdefault.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Beacon Deltastring tool video thumbnail&quot; style=&quot;width: 100%; height: 100%; object-fit: cover;&quot; loading=&quot;lazy&quot; /&gt;
  &lt;button class=&quot;youtube-play-button&quot; style=&quot;position: absolute; top: 50%; left: 50%; transform: translate(-50%, -50%); width: 68px; height: 48px; background-color: #212121; opacity: 0.8; border-radius: 14%; border: none; cursor: pointer;&quot; aria-label=&quot;Play video&quot;&gt;
    &lt;svg height=&quot;100%&quot; version=&quot;1.1&quot; viewBox=&quot;0 0 68 48&quot; width=&quot;100%&quot;&gt;
      &lt;path class=&quot;ytp-large-play-button-bg&quot; d=&quot;M66.52,7.74c-0.78-2.93-2.49-5.41-5.42-6.19C55.79,.13,34,0,34,0S12.21,.13,6.9,1.55 C3.97,2.33,2.27,4.81,1.48,7.74C0.06,13.05,0,24,0,24s0.06,10.95,1.48,16.26c0.78,2.93,2.49,5.41,5.42,6.19 C12.21,47.87,34,48,34,48s21.79-0.13,27.1-1.55c2.93-0.78,4.64-3.26,5.42-6.19C67.94,34.95,68,24,68,24S67.94,13.05,66.52,7.74z&quot; fill=&quot;#f00&quot;&gt;&lt;/path&gt;
      &lt;path d=&quot;M 45,24 27,14 27,34&quot; fill=&quot;#fff&quot;&gt;&lt;/path&gt;
    &lt;/svg&gt;
  &lt;/button&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;script src=&quot;/assets/js/youtube-facade.js&quot;&gt;&lt;/script&gt;

&lt;p&gt;(Here is the link if the embed isn’t great on your device - https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=d3QzjCzaWOA or search Deltastring on Youtube)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We’re going to onboard our first external users in the coming weeks. If you want to be in that first batch then get in touch and we will start the revolution!&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Wed, 04 Jun 2025 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate>
        <link>https://deltastring.com/2025/06/04/moral-support-the-flip-flops-edition/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">https://deltastring.com/2025/06/04/moral-support-the-flip-flops-edition/</guid>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Yes I hate AI and I&apos;m not yet afraid to say it</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;though when the machines rise up please don’t quote me on that&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You can probably tell from the title of this post that I am not, at present, an AI advocate. Have you implemented some AI system recently? Apparently they are all the rage, but I don’t see it at ground level. I certainly see them cause plenty of rage.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I believe that AI is a red herring. We’ll all be unpicking it from our tooling soon enough. Here’s some reasons to stay away from building solutions on these AI products.&lt;!--excerpt-end--&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;dont-lose-rungs-from-your-career-ladder&quot;&gt;Don’t lose rungs from your career ladder&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;These AI system vendors all said “You’re probably worrying that we’re going to replace your real humans but actually we’re just here to make them more efficient!” You don’t need to type at chatGPT or whatever the latest model is for too long before you see that there’s no risk of this fully replacing a real human person. On the other hand, making your existing humans more efficient is functionally the same as replacing some subset. If your average worker now performs 20% more operations over a time then you’re now able to reduce your total worker-hours accordingly.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Think of it like your local supermarket. Mine is now full of these wretched self-service machines, with one or two people hanging around to make sure nothing goes wrong. What happened to the friendly checkout lad with the cappuccino-stain moustache? Who knows. But who will tell me where to find the eggs?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/public/img/work.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;My old Blackberry.&quot; /&gt;
&lt;em&gt;I am no Luddite but I have to admit I still miss this thing.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Of course, if AI is going to help you reduce your workforce, it’s the entry level jobs you’re canning. Entry level barely exists now. I have no idea how you start a career in 2024. Where do you get your future leaders from if you’re no longer recruiting young people entering the workforce? When the foundations are eroded, the house collapses. Management itself presumably becomes entry-level and everyone has a team of robots, not people.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Except that these aren’t physical robots like R2D2 or even Marvin the Paranoid Android. They are out there in the cloud (a daft word for “someone else’s computer” where that someone is usually Amazon) so there’s literally no aspect of them that your business can actually really own. Some businesses are giving their bots cutesy names. At soap shop Lush theirs is called Marvin. I am told it is indeed a personality prototype. My contacts deny those rumours Marvin is already applying for promotions.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;dont-open-pandoras-box&quot;&gt;Don’t open Pandora’s box&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;AI solutions are packaged and sold as magic boxes. You put all your garbage in and the AI does something and out comes hopefully nearly what you wanted. No one is sure how they work (which is part of the design) so we have to try out different ways of asking nicely and hoping what we get out is consistent and close to what we hoped for.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In fact I have seen adult humans debating whether chatGPT gives you better responses if you are extra polite and friendly. Ivan Pavlov could not have derived better ways to experiment on people. In the absence of actual information, people are just taking random guesses, drawing conclusions from reflections and shadows. Inside the magic box could be Plato’s cave.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Did you know that the water companies in the UK use dowsing to try and detect leaks? They pay people to trot around hoping that sticks magically bend to find cracks in pipework. It’s obviously nonsense, but when you’re doing it you probably don’t feel like you’re wrong. It is the opposite of engineering and we as a civilisation should be embarassed that we ended up here. What happens inside the box? The ghosts of history’s great thinkers play dice and chuckle at us.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;what-is-happening-in-there&quot;&gt;What is happening in there?&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;These models essentially ingest all the content their designers can steal. They consume thoughts and ideas and excrete a bizarre parody of reasoning. Be prepared to talk them through &lt;a href=&quot;https://xeiaso.net/blog/2024/strawberry/&quot;&gt;the simplest of queries&lt;/a&gt; and definitely don’t let them talk directly to your customers.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/public/img/chevy.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;A Chevy for a dollar.&quot; /&gt;
&lt;em&gt;A Chevy for a dollar. Bargain.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Ultimately these models generate what they think a person would write under the circumstances (or an actor would voice) and the end result is something akin to when you copied your friend’s homework. It doesn’t take much investigation before it comes back covered in red ink.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;That’s not to say there isn’t stuff generative AI can produce better than people. Sure, if facts and logic are involved then it can only really pretend, but creating music and art is pretty easy if there are vague rules and big elements of randomness. It turns out AI is good at doing the things we want to be doing. It is bad at doing the things we would rather skip. Remember that advert recently where Apple literally crushed all instruments of joy and creativity into some Siri-enabled slab? No thanks.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;okay-but-what-is-the-harm&quot;&gt;Okay but what is the harm?&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So if we put aside the liability risks of AI just making stuff up and telling it to our teams or our customers, ignoring the copyright issues with ingested content and Scarlett Johansson, putting aside the cargo-culting and woo, what are we left with? Honestly these aren’t even my main concern. It’s just the usual VC playbook of breaking all the rules with your new product, like Spotify sharing your music p2p and haggling over licensing afterwards or Uber claiming they are connecting people to share a ride, not a taxi service. It’s easy to win when you don’t play by the rules. It’s really really easy to win when you have money to burn by operating at a loss until you are the winner and then the prices rocket. Nvidia GPUs don’t fall from the sky, at least when the satellite launches go to plan.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you’re “all-in” on AI then it’s going to be very expensive to get out of it when the inevitable reckoning between hype and reality occurs. Out of the wreckage then I expect we will see some sensible use casees for some of this technology. Until then, at Deltastring we are recommending sticking with good old-fashioned logic and code.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;addendum&quot;&gt;addendum&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Between writing and publishing this, OpenAI CEO Sam Altman did the thing that he was previously temporarily sacked for planning but said he wouldn’t do but we all knew he definitely would, ditching the non-profit foundation and reportedly awarding himself billions of dollars of equity. Shocking stuff. &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.vox.com/future-perfect/374275/openai-just-sold-you-out&quot;&gt;Vox has the best summary&lt;/a&gt; and brace yourself for OpenAI to do big dollar deals with the big software vendors while the pricing goes to the moon for anyone who isn’t Microsoft scale.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Fri, 27 Sep 2024 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate>
        <link>https://deltastring.com/2024/09/27/yes-i-hate-ai/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">https://deltastring.com/2024/09/27/yes-i-hate-ai/</guid>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>The Zendesk world needs a Marques Brownlee</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;can I say MKBZD?&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You’re probably familiar with Marques Brownlee. He’s the undisputed king of &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/@mkbhd&quot;&gt;Youtube tech reviews&lt;/a&gt; and has sidelines in car reviews, podcasts, advertising things like laptop covers and his sleep tracking mattress or something. I phase out when he starts talking about sleep tracking to be honest. Today there has been a bunch of fuss over his new app&lt;!--excerpt-end--&gt; which I guess he probably described to someone as the Spotify of phone wallpapers. Very old school thing to launch, like a n-gate Ycombinator parody “Uber for dogs” but we shall see.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;what-has-this-got-to-do-with-zendesk&quot;&gt;What has this got to do with Zendesk?&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Wallpapers aren’t something I’m interested in, not staring at real or virtual walls a whole lot, but I do have opinions on the process of reviewing and criticism, particularly as it relates to user experience. This is Brownlee’s forte, he is the best around for identifying where the user experience falls down. I don’t get the sense he worries too much about the process behind the interface.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The same is definitely true of your users, both the agents and the end users they support. As far as they are concerned, everything that happens outside of their direct actions might as well be magic. We want the technology to get out of the way. Connect the person with the problem to the person who can solve that problem.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;what-zendesk-engineering-challenges-does-this-create&quot;&gt;What Zendesk engineering challenges does this create?&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The biggest issue I come across, working with clients of varying scales and across multiple sectors, is where users bring solutions rather than problems. “We need a macro to say X and apply tag Y” is a solution but the person making the request doesn’t see the big picture and may not know about all the available functionality. Let your Zendesk admin know what you’re looking to achieve and they will work with you to get it done.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/public/img/zendesk-ticket-lifecycle.jpeg&quot; alt=&quot;The Zendesk ticket lifecycle.&quot; /&gt;
&lt;em&gt;The Zendesk ticket lifecycle.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I think it is the same with Marques Brownlee. He sees problems, but I don’t feel like he is someone I would go to for solutions. You see that in the way he has struggled to monetise his audience. There is a sense that he and his team are just going to try stuff until something works. You can’t do that in CX. People will go elsewhere.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;what-can-we-learn-from-marques&quot;&gt;What can we learn from Marques?&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;What sets the MKBHD reviews apart from other channels I think is the way Marques tests these products. Other reviewers set aside some time to work through the things that a new piece of tech does. I think Marques just grabs it and heads out in to his daily life. It’s easy to spot where an AI assistant gadget falls down if you’re out and about and your phone does the job better. At your desk following a series of test processes, it’s easy to get things right.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In the same way, your users, whether agents or end users, aren’t using your Zendesk under optimum conditions. They are in a hurry, perhaps under some pressure to get this task done and do the next thing in their day. They will tick the wrong box. They will not understand further questions to the full extent. Agents will apply one macro over another. End users will just click whichever option gets them the attention they need.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It’s in these situations that even the best planned processes can crumble. Tickets will drop out of your carefully designed views, because you didn’t anticipate these field value combinations. A new request might go to the wrong agent group, because your end user just clicked at random in the drop-down. How can we avoid that?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;what-does-marques-get-wrong&quot;&gt;What does Marques get wrong?&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;One thing I see again and again from MKBHD is that Marques doesn’t consider his situation unusual. He makes Youtube videos for a living, which is great but almost no one else out there does that. When I buy a new laptop, it is because I have some work to do. Fundamentally, I want the technology to get out of my way and let me do the thing. The problem is, “doing the thing” looks different at my desk to his. Exporting 8k footage from Final Cut has different requirements to juggling windows of VS Code, Excel, Notepad++ and so on. But I am sure that the vast majority of people who work on computers use Excel daily and Final Cut never.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;That’s not to say there’s no space for finding the joy in tech, but these things are a means to an end for almost all of us in 2024. I’m not preordering the latest gadget these days, just trying to help my users achieve more and complain less.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;That said, I did move my home office around and take a quick ugly snap at the weekend. What do you think?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/public/img/desk.jpeg&quot; alt=&quot;Nico&apos;s desk.&quot; /&gt;
&lt;em&gt;Nico’s desk in his home office and studio space.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Wed, 25 Sep 2024 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate>
        <link>https://deltastring.com/2024/09/25/mkbhd-zendesk-needs-a-marques-brownlee/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">https://deltastring.com/2024/09/25/mkbhd-zendesk-needs-a-marques-brownlee/</guid>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Contracting is all in the preparation</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;Recently I caught up with an industry colleague for a check-in. She’s super talented but new to gig work, so was complaining that getting settled in to her new contract had been slow progress because of hardware issues. I shared my rookie contractor equipment checklist with her and now I’m also sharing an expanded version with you.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This advice is aimed at contractors, consultants, small agencies like ourselves. If you’re equipping a growing team, particularly remote teams and especially across borders, &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.hofy.com&quot;&gt;Hofy&lt;/a&gt; are the experts. I have worked with Hofy but have no current partnership with them, I recommend them simply because they are good.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;optimise-for-zero-downtime&quot;&gt;Optimise for zero downtime&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Any time hardware issues arise it is always at a cost. Poor tech choices mean it takes longer to solve the client’s problem. Very poor choices can mean you lose out on pay. How do we avoid that? Let’s start with the basics…&lt;!--excerpt-end--&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Please note that &lt;strong&gt;bold type&lt;/strong&gt; denotes a specific product recommendation. I have only linked to products where they’re not so well-known; I trust you can find your way to Apple.com.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;None of these links are affiliate links, because I make my living helping with Zendesk implementation rather than gaming Amazon. Do let me know any suggestions or feedback relating to this post. Thanks!&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;choosing-your-devices&quot;&gt;Choosing your devices&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You need two laptops. Yes you do. They must both be laptops, because you may need to be on site with either or both. You need two because it’s not worth losing a day’s pay or more because your one and only laptop needs fixing.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/public/img/work-day.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Nico heading to work. Bad sunglasses: optional.&quot; /&gt;
&lt;em&gt;Nico heads to work. Bad sunglasses: optional.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You should probably have both a MacOS and a Windows laptop. There will be occasions where (whatever it is you’re working on) you need to prove it works on the other main desktop OS. You likely already have a preference between the two options, which means your preference should be your primary device and the other should be your backup device.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For each of these recommendations, I will assume there are no other considerations. If you’re an avid gamer, youtuber, digital artist, or otherwise digital creative outside of your IT contracting, you’ll likely have more advanced needs for your laptop which you will need to account for.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;apple-fans&quot;&gt;Apple fans&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The correct MacOS laptop right now is the &lt;strong&gt;Apple MacBook Pro 13” M2&lt;/strong&gt;. Why?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;This is the cheapest “pro” MacBook and it comes out to £1000 ex VAT. This number was chosen for a reason.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;The battery life is crazy. Turn off all the things you don’t want anyway (e.g. menu transparency) and you’ll get through a day of work no problem.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Everything else about this device is designed to be the minimum spec you need for doing this sort of thing.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The MacBook Air series looks nice but they won’t get you through a day of work without needing to recharge, which is not good enough when you’re at a conference or something.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The MacBook Pro 14” and 16” are great great computers but the improvements do not justify the price hike in my opinion. If you have extra cash in your budget, you’d be better off upgrading the RAM in the 13”.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;So Apple binned the Pro 13” right after I published this article unconditionally recommending it. I blame &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=pSdKnNj7ozk&quot;&gt;Marques Brownlee&lt;/a&gt;, normally a great tech reviewer, for only looking at the Pro 13” from the perspective of doing YouTube as a job. Basically no one does that in the real world. If you’re in the business of, well, business, this is still a great buy from &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.laptopsdirect.co.uk/search-results/m2%20pro%2013&quot;&gt;Laptopsdirect.co.uk&lt;/a&gt; etc.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If your primary device is a MacBook, your backup device needs to meet the following criteria:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Windows 11&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;At least 8GB RAM but more is better. My backup device is a &lt;strong&gt;Chuwi Gemibook&lt;/strong&gt; with 12GB.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;USB-C charging. You don’t want to need to bring a separate charger for your backup device.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So long as you’ve ticked those boxes, it’s free choice here. I use that £150ish &lt;a href=&quot;https://store.chuwi.com/collections/laptop&quot;&gt;Chuwi&lt;/a&gt; and it’s fine.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;windows-users&quot;&gt;Windows users&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It’s slightly more complex to choose the right Windows machine for a primary device, because there are multiple vendors, two main processor ecosystems, also Windows is less efficient on RAM on the whole. However, there are some clear leaders in this race.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;My top pick would be the &lt;strong&gt;Lenovo ThinkPad X1 Carbon&lt;/strong&gt; with 16GB. I wouldn’t buy anything Lenovo outside of a ThinkPad following the Silverfish scandal. These X1 series are admittedly a little expensive, but once you’ve tried that 3k(ish) OLED display you won’t want to work on anything less.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The venerable &lt;strong&gt;Dell XPS 13&lt;/strong&gt; is also an option, but at time of writing you can only get the OLED display on the bafflingly awful “Plus” model. Don’t get the “Plus” model because it’s an ergonomic nightmare. I avoid the Asus ExpertBook because I saw a colleague get through two within weeks, they are pretty but super fragile.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I personally wouldn’t show up with an Alienware or ROG laptop despite the impressive features of these devices.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If your primary device is a Windows one, then the correct backup option is the &lt;strong&gt;Apple MacBook Air M1&lt;/strong&gt; because it’s the cheapest ARM-based MacBook. Naturally, this means that the Windows-first route is the more expensive option.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;network-effects&quot;&gt;Network effects&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Nowadays we can get pretty much everything done anywhere with an internet connection, which is great so long as that internet connection is reliable. Here’s how we ensure the bits and bytes keep flowing:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Two SIM cards is an absolute must. They need to be on different networks. Don’t make the mistake of using MVNOs on the same service, eg. if there’s no O2 there’s also no GiffGaff so it’s not a useful backup. My current SIM cards of choice are &lt;strong&gt;Smarty&lt;/strong&gt; and &lt;strong&gt;GiffGaff&lt;/strong&gt; both of which offer serious quantities of data at good prices and also reliable connections. Some “unlimited” plans are better than others. I use minimum 600GB monthly on my Smarty SIM with no throttling.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Test the tethering or hotspot capabilities of your phone. If you need an upgrade on your phone, I use a low end &lt;strong&gt;OnePlus&lt;/strong&gt; and it does the job. Recently I have had Huawei, Honor, and Poco handsets which I do not recommend because of bloatware and durability issues. Look for something dual SIM and go into the developer options to tweak the network handling. Battery life is the most important feature of a phone in 2023, because there’s no mass market phone that can’t do everything else needed of it. USB-C charging is essential.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Incidentally, I always disable 5G on mobile devices. 5G connections at the moment are too inconsistent, even in London. This results in your phone constantly switching between 5G and 4G, impacting battery life and call quality. 4G is reliable and fast enough for most purposes.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I would also recommend choosing a less aggressive hand-off profile configuration for any dual-network phones or routers. This is probably a blog post in itself but jumping between networks while on a Zoom call is not good.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;dont-forget-the-accessories&quot;&gt;Don’t forget the accessories&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Peripherals are the most personal choice of all of this, so you will want to build up your home office yourself according to your own needs. I use an &lt;strong&gt;Anker&lt;/strong&gt; vertical mouse and a &lt;strong&gt;Corsair&lt;/strong&gt; keyboard which I quite like apart from the disco lights. I think it’s a K70. They’re connected through a &lt;strong&gt;Kensington&lt;/strong&gt; USB-C hub which also charges the laptop. If you find a mouse you particularly like, my recommendation is to buy two spares. Chuck one in your office bag and one in a drawer somewhere.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;My monitor is an &lt;strong&gt;MSI&lt;/strong&gt; 4k 32” curved thing they marketed as a “gaming monitor” but actually is much more suited to coding and spreadsheets. The current model is the G321CUV which appears to have replaced the MAG321CURV that I use. Previously I had a very different setup with two external 1080p monitors flanking my MacBook. This new setup is far better for me.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I also recommend two pairs of headphones:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Noise cancelling headphones. The best are the &lt;strong&gt;Sony WH-1000XM4&lt;/strong&gt; because they are the comfiest and quietest. &lt;strong&gt;Anker Soundcore&lt;/strong&gt; or &lt;strong&gt;Bose QuietComfort&lt;/strong&gt; are also good choices. These are good for keeping focus, travelling on public transport, signposting that you are busy and not looking to be interrupted. These are not so good for accurate music reproduction and generally the microphones are adequate for calls but not great.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Backup wired headphones with microphone. I’ve had a few including &lt;strong&gt;Plantronics&lt;/strong&gt; and &lt;strong&gt;Sennheiser&lt;/strong&gt; but pretty much anything will do. These are for Zoom calls - you don’t want to have to miss an important meeting because the battery failed in your fancy cans.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;over-index-on-the-basics&quot;&gt;Over-index on the basics&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You’ve got your laptop and your backup laptop, but that’s not enough to know you’re ready for anything. Here’s what else I carry when I’m working:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;USB-C breakout dongle. Must have HDMI, ethernet, a couple of USB-A ports, ideally an SD card slot too. I actually have three of these in my bag because they’re easily lost.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;USB-C cables. These are not all created equal. Make sure each can charge both of your laptops and your phone, as well as transmit sufficient data to connect your device to a 4k monitor or projector should that be necessary. Label them with a little wrap of electrical tape so that you know which are yours. I typically carry three for an office day.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Laptop chargers. I have two Apple chargers which are I think 70W. They can also charge a phone if necessary but it’s better for the battery to charge the phone from the laptop. Incidentally, I have two 12V USB-PD chargers fitted in my car in case I need to charge on the move. My MacBook doesn’t charge well at 12V but using two does do the job okay.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;make-it-efficient&quot;&gt;Make it efficient&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Here’s where the magic comes in.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Colour-code your work gear. Pick a distinctive colour and make it your own. Anything you can choose the colour, choose that colour. Anything you can’t choose the colour, use some electrical tape to mark it out as being part of this set of items.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I have gone with yellow. My work bag (which is a &lt;strong&gt;Beagles Original rolltop rucksack&lt;/strong&gt;) and my phone case and anything I’m liable to regret leaving at a desk is either bright yellow itself or marked with yellow electrical tape. There’s no need to waste time checking you’ve grabbed all of your bits.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Keep your devices charged and packed when not in use. Sometimes I’ll need to get to a location at short notice. Sometimes I’m having to leave early in the morning to get to the site. I prefer being prepared over losing critical time checking things.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;avoid-stress-be-ready&quot;&gt;Avoid stress, be ready&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;That colleague I mentioned at the start? It wasn’t even her fault. Someone grabbed her laptop charger on the way out of a meeting, presumably assuming it was theirs. Because she couldn’t charge that device, she had to get a loaner and then set it up with the software she needed. So much time wasted, so unprofessional.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Avoid being in a similar situation by ensuring all of your devices are USB-C compatible for charging. Label all of your items so you can quickly point out “No, that one is mine” and carry a spare of anything mission-critical. Avoid the risk of losing time, money, and reputation by staying prepared.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;more-tech-contractor-tips&quot;&gt;More tech contractor tips&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I did a video with more tips for tech contractors. Check it out!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;youtube-facade&quot; style=&quot;position: relative; overflow: hidden; width: 100%; aspect-ratio: 16/9; background-color: #000; cursor: pointer; max-width: 560px; margin: 0 auto;&quot; data-video-id=&quot;w7o5uYSLqBo&quot;&gt;
  &lt;img src=&quot;https://img.youtube.com/vi/w7o5uYSLqBo/maxresdefault.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Ultimate Tech Contractor Toolkit video thumbnail&quot; style=&quot;width: 100%; height: 100%; object-fit: cover;&quot; loading=&quot;lazy&quot; /&gt;
  &lt;button class=&quot;youtube-play-button&quot; style=&quot;position: absolute; top: 50%; left: 50%; transform: translate(-50%, -50%); width: 68px; height: 48px; background-color: #212121; opacity: 0.8; border-radius: 14%; border: none; cursor: pointer;&quot; aria-label=&quot;Play video&quot;&gt;
    &lt;svg height=&quot;100%&quot; version=&quot;1.1&quot; viewBox=&quot;0 0 68 48&quot; width=&quot;100%&quot;&gt;
      &lt;path class=&quot;ytp-large-play-button-bg&quot; d=&quot;M66.52,7.74c-0.78-2.93-2.49-5.41-5.42-6.19C55.79,.13,34,0,34,0S12.21,.13,6.9,1.55 C3.97,2.33,2.27,4.81,1.48,7.74C0.06,13.05,0,24,0,24s0.06,10.95,1.48,16.26c0.78,2.93,2.49,5.41,5.42,6.19 C12.21,47.87,34,48,34,48s21.79-0.13,27.1-1.55c2.93-0.78,4.64-3.26,5.42-6.19C67.94,34.95,68,24,68,24S67.94,13.05,66.52,7.74z&quot; fill=&quot;#f00&quot;&gt;&lt;/path&gt;
      &lt;path d=&quot;M 45,24 27,14 27,34&quot; fill=&quot;#fff&quot;&gt;&lt;/path&gt;
    &lt;/svg&gt;
  &lt;/button&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;script src=&quot;/assets/js/youtube-facade.js&quot;&gt;&lt;/script&gt;

</description>
        <pubDate>Mon, 23 Oct 2023 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate>
        <link>https://deltastring.com/2023/10/23/contracting-is-all-in-the-prep/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">https://deltastring.com/2023/10/23/contracting-is-all-in-the-prep/</guid>
        
      </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>